Steven Vallarsa

#READYFORWORK After careers in graphic design, newspaper publication, sign making, artwork reproduction, and manufacturing production, I've reignited my long dormant passion for coding. Starting with a few online courses, I ramped up my education by successfully completing bootcamps in C# .NET as well as full-stack JavaScript web and mobile development. In the past year I have also completed career-track training in Java and am now working through a full-stack JavaScript "Techdegree" program in order to keep my skillset up to date. I bring with me a lifetime of diverse experiences that makes me an outstanding candidate to fill positions where I may be nurtured to quickly grow and blossom into mid- and senior-level roles within the organization.

EDUCATION

- TreeHouse | June August 2022 | Full-Stack JavaScript project-based Techdegree
- Cook Systems | April 2022 | Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MapStruct, Postman
- mThree | November December 2021 | Java Software Development: Maven, Spring Boot MVC, JDBC, ThymeLeaf, REST API, MySQL
- **NuCamp** | June October 2021 | Full-Stack + Mobile Development: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, React Native, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB
- Grand Circus | April June 2019 | C# .NET Software Development: OOP, MVC, APIs, SQL, Git
- Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology | Associate of Arts | Graphic Design
- University of Toronto | Bachelor of Science | Astronomy

CERTIFICATIONS

- Salesforce Administrator | Salesforce
- Certified ScrumMaster | Scrum Alliance
- ITIL Foundation | AXELOS

- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt | Lean Sigma Corporation
- Technical Writing | Western Michigan University

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

L3 Application Support Engineer | COOK SYSTEMS / FEDEX GROUND | Remote | May – Aug 2022

- Manage end-user access by modifying permissions and solving access difficulties.
- Diagnose and correct database discrepancies to ensure accuracy of outputs throughout internal company applications by crafting custom SQL scripts.
- Discover root cause for database inconsistencies between observed inputs and expected outputs.

Associate Software Developer | DART CONTAINER | Remote | May 2020 - November 2020

- Worked through support tickets in C# and JavaScript to track down bugs and help resolve user issues with internal software systems.
- Added endpoint to salesperson portal by pair programming with intermediate developer.
- Earned Salesforce Administration and Certified ScrumMaster certifications.
- Participated in Scrum sprints and introduced to the workings of backend Azure administration.

Web Developer | CHAMELEON POWER | Novi, MI | February 2020 – February 2020

• On team of developers that modified existing JavaScript visual display applications to suit needs of new and existing clients by working through production tickets to eliminate bugs and solve problems.

Developer I | NEXIENT | Ann Arbor, MI | October 2019 – December 2019

• Upgraded skills in backend development through C# and .NET core, database design and management through SQL, and frontend development through HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Blazor and React.

Student Developer | GRAND CIRCUS PROJECT | Grand Rapids, MI | June 2019 – August 2019

- On team of student developers that crafted an air quality application from scratch using the C# language in .NET Core and Framework with Visual Studio 2019.
- Imported air quality readings from databases hosting sensor data, and used a weather forecast API to calculate current and predicted Air Quality Indexes for user's location by triangulating position of closest sensor via Google Maps API.

Steven Vallarsa

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

Press Operator | ADVANCE PACKAGING | Grand Rapids, MI | October 2018

• Kept track of order sequence to install correct printing plates and dies, and loaded correct cardboard for the current job, and set up and maintained hopper for stable operation.

Insurance Sales | SELF-EMPLOYED | Grandville, MI | May 2018 – September 2018

• Met with clients to assess their situation, and matched policy options that fit their needs and budget.

Technical Operator | LG CHEM MICHIGAN | Holland, MI | June 2015 – October 2017

- Managed high-quality manufacturing operations in lithium battery cell production.
- Led quality functions to ensure technical consistency across production.
- Recorded daily service and operations results using technical forms and production logs.
- Established priorities for the maintenance of production system and equipment.
- Promoted quality manufacturing, lean production, and continuous improvement by authoring proposal to retrain operators in best practices to curtail wasted downtime and loss of materials that would have improved throughput enough to eliminate one Saturday of overtime a month.

Machine Operator | THE STOW COMPANY | Holland, MI | October 2013 – June 2015

- Programmed and operated a variety of industrial panel saws, edgebanders, drill presses, and other manufacturing equipment used in the production of wood shelving.
- Cleaned and maintained equipment, and performed regular tool changes.
- Consistently delivered on KPI measures within machining operations, including safety compliance, quality standards, cost control, process reliability and production volume.
- Developed a system of roller board standardization, sorting and return, allowing saw operators to run their equipment without unnecessary interruption.

Production Manager | MICHIGAN CUSTOM SIGNS | Holland, MI | November 2009 - April 2013

- Served as lead designer, managed in-house production operations, and carried out duties in client support and customer service, including POS to generate invoices and track financials.
- Worked with clients to create eye-catching signs, from initial concepts to final products, by developing graphics and illustrations with Illustrator and Photoshop in Adobe Creative Suite.
- Operated and maintained large format Roland SOLJET printer and large format laminator.
- Managed purchasing and inventory control to make sure materials were available when needed.

Graphic Designer | SIGNS NOW HOLLAND | Holland, MI | July 2001 – July 2007

- Created eye-catching sign designs from salespeople's copy in Gerber Advantage and Adobe Illustrator.
- Managed work orders and completed design and vinyl tasks in a timely and efficient manner so as to keep table production running smoothly.
- Operated and maintained vinyl plotters and thermal printer, and ordered supplies.

Production Manager | SOUTH SIDE STORY | Sudbury , ON | November 1995 - December 2000

- Managed ad production and final layout for monthly newspaper using QuarkXPress, Macromedia FreeHand and Adobe Photoshop.
- Created eye-catching ads from salespeople's copy.
- Inputted copy and ads, scanned photos, and created graphics for insertion into issue.
- Supervised creation of film negatives and printing production to maximize use and reduce waste.

Graphic Designer | SELF-EMPLOYED | Various Locations | May 1994 – December 2015

- Provided clients with custom solutions with graphic design, illustration, websites, printed materials, logos and marketing solutions using Adobe and Macromedia software suites.
- Managed day-to-day operations of small business.
- Operated and maintained computer systems and large format printing equipment.
- Provided training and instruction in computer operation and graphic design, including production of custom reference materials.